Guide to the Gould Colman papers, 1954-1996.
Colman, Gould papers,
- Lectures, papers, and conference presentations, 1961-1987
  - "Contented Cows and Dairy Maids: Patriarchy and Capitalism in American Agriculture" by Sarah Elbert, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "American Farm Women in Historical Perspective" conference materials, 1986-10 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - "Battle Plan for St. Paul", 1987-10 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Abstracts - Farm Women Program, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Farm Stress group materials, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - "Summary of Major Findings from American Farm Women: Findings from a National Survey" by Calvin Jones and Rachel Rosenfeld, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - "The Historical Roots of Occupational Sexism" by Heidi Hartmann, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - "Inventory of the family's human resources and procedures for use", 1980-01-16 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - "Art, Occupation, and Mystery: Making Decisions in U.S. Farming" article drafts and correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Art, Occupation, and Mystery: Making Decisions in U.S. Farming", 1983 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "The Division of Labor in Families and the Development of Adolescent Farm Girls in the 1970s" by Janet Kalinowski, 1982-05 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Papers for Rural Sociological Society conference, Farm Family session, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Farm Women press release, 1982-08 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Psychological Stress Among Farm Women" by Alan Berkowitz, 1982-10 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Farm Husbands and Wives in Wisconsin" by Eugene A. Wilkening, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "The Farm", Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cooperstown seminar - not given, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Conference concerning research on farm women, 1982-11 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Farm Women in Historical Perspective" conference materials, 1984-02 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Extension in-service training schedule and notes, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Int. Agr." Conference notes, 1983-10-10 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Two Road Lecture" notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Lecture notes, 1985-05 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Sam Todd", 1985-05 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Lecture notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "The Farm" lecture notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "Farm Family" lecture, SUNY Binghamton, 1979-03 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Farm wives lecture notes, 1979-11 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "Farm Family" lecture notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - "Farm family" seminar, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Farm Families: What Are Good Decisions" lecture notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "The History pf Agricultural Education at Cornell University" correspondence and notes, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - "Pioneering in Agricultural Education: Cornell University", Undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Course materials, 1981-1984
  - Agricultural Economics 150 answer key, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Farming lecture: notes and course reading lists, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Rural Sociology 417: Farm Families: How They Make Decisions and Set Goals course materials, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - R.S. 417 course materials, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - R.S. 102 lecture notes, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Miscellaneous, 1970-2014
  - Copy of NAFTA letter signed by five presidents, 1993-11-16 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Includes letter from Robert Pastor at the Carter Center explaining how the NAFTA letter was created and signed.
  - Newspaper comics, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Envelope from Cooperative Extension Service, Montana State University, 1987-06-09 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Contains photos, newspaper clippings, and "Addition to 'Ranching.'"
  - "The Grapevine Notebook", 1979-09 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - "Evaluating the NY FarmNet Program", 1987-10 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Sarah Elbert curriculum vita, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Book review photocopies, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - "Farming Alternatives Project", Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - "Jewish comes up in you from the roots" by Bobbe-Myseh, Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Auction list newspaper clippings, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - USDA publications, Undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - "A Philosopher Among Economists" by John Brewster photocopy, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Paarlberg articles photocopies, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Barley magic lantern show, Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Empty folder.
  - Articles and notes, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "Food and Life Science Quarterly", 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - "Farm Woman National Report", 1979-05-07 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Articles on farm stress, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - "Cornell alumni news", 1979-02 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Bill Fogle Residential Club fire files, 2013-2014 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Prints of historic Cornell photos, Undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    Photographs from the Alumni Affairs/Archives Photo Exhibit, used in Barton Hall during Reunion Week in 1987. They were available to Cornell class of 1987 alumni for purchase.
  - Prints of historic Cornell photos, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)